Suresh Kumar

Developer

E-mail – sureshyadavndls@gmail.com

Contact – +918010614774

UI designer/Front-End

Date of Birth – 25/01/1986

Location – Noida, UP

SUMMARY

Frontend Developer with 9+ Years of total experience in UI designing / Front-End Development using CSS/CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, JQuery, Angular 4-13, Bootstrap, Dreamweaver, specialization in WordPress Theme Customization, Photoshop, Corel Draw, Illustrator, Domain/Hosting Configure.

Angular 4-13 (Responsive UI design / Front-end develop design in Angular), PSD to HTML5, PSD to Angular, Wireframe to HTML5, HTML5 landing page, Emailer, UI design in HTML5 and Angular, Domain & Hosting Configure experience.

SKILLS

| UI Design and Development | Responsive website designing | PSD to wordpress |
|-------------------------------|----------------------------------|-----------------------------------|
| Front-end Development | Responsive Landing development | E-blast, Emailer, Email Signature |
| | and design | |
| Lead - UX and UI Design | PSD to HTML5 Responsive | PSD to Angular design and |
| | | frontend development |
| Wordpress them customization, | Megento frontend design | Wireframe to HTML5 |
| Woocommerce, | | |
| SSL configuration | Domain and Hosting Configuration | FTTP Handling |

TECHNICAL SKILLS

| HTML5 | Jquery | Dreamweaver |
|------------|--------------|-------------------------|
| CSS 2 & 3 | Angular 5-13 | Photoshop CS6 |
| JavaScript | Bootstrap | Illustrator, Corel DRaw |

EXPERIENCE

Sep 3, 2018 – Present: US4 Business Solutions Pvt Ltd, Gurugram, www.us4group.com

Designation – Sr. Front-end Developer

Project – https://www.edhacare.com/, <a href="https://www.edh

Responsibilities – Wireframe and PSD to HTML5/Angular Responsive, UI Design in HTML5 and Angular, Data display API to Angular, TDF and Reactive forms development in Angular, Wordpress theme customization. **Skills** – **HTML5**, **CSS**, **Javascript**, **JQuery**, **Angular**, **Bootstrap**, **Wordpress**, **PhotoShop**

Feb 6, 2018 - Aug 2018: London School of International Business (LSIB), UK, lsib.co.uk

DLF Tower - A Jasola New Delhi.

Designation – Sr. Front-end Developer

Project – https://www.travelcourses.org/, http://www.lsba.org.uk/, https://www.lsba.org.uk/, http://www.studyuniv.com/, http://www.studyuniv.com/)

Responsibilities – Wireframe/PSD to HTML5/ Responsive, Landing page, Emailer, Wordpress theme customization.

Feb 2015 – Jan 2018: FAMILY SHOP 18 www.familyshop18.com , (Varanasi) Uttar Pradesh. **Designation** – Team Leader (Sr. Front-end Developer)

Responsibilities – Responsive Web Design, Landing page design for PPC, Magneto Theme and Extension Customization.

E-commerce Website Services Management (SKU Manage, Courier, Product Packing, Product Shipping) etc.

May 2014 – Jan 2015: Pinnacle Technology, https://www.pinnacle-technology.com/, Sector-63, Noida. Designation – Sr. Web designer

Project – http://premiereaesthetics.com/,

Responsibilities: PSD To HTML Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Landing page HTML for PPC, E-blast, Flash Banner, Logo Design,

Dec 2012 – April 2014: Jingle Infotech Limited, https://www.jingleinfotech.com/ LajpatNagar , New Delhi. Designation – Sr. Web Designer

Project – http://www.shapesbrowbar.com/, <a href="

Responsibilities – PSD To HTML (table base & table less), Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Landing page HTML for PPC, E-blast, Make PSD Template/UI PSD/Flash Banner, Logo Design,

Jan 2012 - Sep 2012 - SPCITS, Rohini, New Delhi

Designation – Jr. Web designer

Project – http://www.drdo.gov.in, http://www.ndtvjewels.com, <a href="http://www.ndtvjewels

Responsibilities – PSD To HTML (Table base & table less), Graphics Design, flash,

EDUCATION

- MCA from Swami Vivekanand Subharti University, Meerut 2021.
- B.Com. from V.B.S. Purvanchal University, Jaunpur in 2007.
- 12th from U.P. Board Allahabad in 2003.
- 10th from U.P. Board Allahabad in 2001.

CERTIFICATION

- Advance Diploma In Computer Application & Web Designing ADCA-WEB, GIIT Mughalsarai in 2010.
- Flash from Lal Bahadur Shastri Training Institute, Laxmi Nagar, New Delhi in 2012.
- Hardware Chip Level & Card Level from Hi-Tech Noida in 2011.

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Father's Name -- Mr. Khedaroo
- Language -- English, Hindi.
- Permanent Address -- H. No. 1102, Subhash Nagar, Mughalsarai, Chandauli, Uttar Pradesh-232101.
- Passport yes

OTHER INTERESTS

- Learning new Technologies
- Traveling

DECLARATION

I am ready to work in India and abroad. I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date:

Place: Noida (Suresh Kumar)